Hello, welcome back. So in this video and notebook,
大家好 欢迎回来 在此视频和 notebook 中
I'm going to be talking about inference and validation.
我将介绍推理和验证
So, inference means when we have
推理是指训练网络后
a tree network and we're using our network to make predictions.
我们将使用网络做出预测
So neural networks have this issue where they have
神经网络存在一个问题
a tendency to perform too well on the training data,
容易在训练数据上表现太好
and they aren't able to generalize to other data.
无法泛化到其他数据
So for instance, if you traded on a bunch of
例如 如果用大量图像训练了网络
images and then you give it an image that it hasn't seen before,
然后输入一个没见过的图像
it would do a really poor job at predicting what's in that image.
网络在预测该图像中的内容方面将表现很糟糕
So neural networks learn from the training data too much and they're bad at generalizing,
神经网络从训练数据中学习了太多细节 无法泛化
this is called overfitting.
这称为过拟合
So the test for overfitting while training,
为了在训练过程中测试是否过拟合
we perform inference with our network on a test set or our validation set.
我们用网络对测试集或验证集进行推理
So this is the set of data that looks like the training data,
这个数据集看起来像训练集
but it's not in the training set,
但是不在训练集中
so basically the neural network hasn't seen this data before.
神经网络之前没有见过此数据
So that way when we're testing on this validation set,
这样的话 当我们在验证集上测试时
we can see how well the network is able to generalize to data it hasn't seen before.
可以看出网络泛化到之前没见过的数据的效果
To get started, I'm going to import our packages like PyTorch towards vision like normal.
首先 正常地导入 PyTorch torchvision 等软件包
Here again, I am loading the fashion hymnist dataset.
再次加载 FashionMNIST 数据集
You'll notice here that I'm delegating the test data,
你将发现 我在这里下载了测试数据
so this is the data that we're going be using for validation.
我们将使用此数据进行验证
So we have this data, the training data,
这是训练数据
that we're going to get from the train set and train loader,
从训练集 trainloader 中获取
and we have our test validation data from test loader.
这是从 testloader 中获取的测试验证数据
So here, I built a network that it's a bit more advanced than what I've shown you so
在此处 我构建了一个比到目前为止构建的网络更高级的网络
far because I wanted to have an arbitrary number of hidden layers.
因为我希望有任意数量的隐藏层
So basically, I wanted to be able to pass in a list like this,
我希望传入像这样的列表
and then it will automatically build
然后它将自动构建三个隐藏层
three hidden layers with this number of units in each of those layers.
每个层级具有这么多数量的单元
So to do this I used nn.ModuleList, and basically,
为此 我使用了 nn.ModuleList
the idea is that it works like a normal list, where you can add things to it and extend it
它和普通列表很像 你可以向其中添加内容 扩展它 等等
and so on, but the model is able to PyTorch models,
但是 PyTorch 模型能够跟踪
able to track the modules that you're adding to this module list.
你添加到此模块列表中的模块
Because otherwise if you just use a normal list,
如果使用普通列表的话
then PyTorch wouldn't be able to track that,
PyTorch 将无法跟踪
and you wouldn't see those modules and operations ending up in your model.
你无法看到模型中的这些模块和运算
I'm not going get too much into how this works,
我就不详细讲解原理了
because I wrote it out here,
因为我已经写在这里了
so feel free to read all this at your leisure.
你可以在空闲时阅读这段内容
The major things that you should note in this new network is that I've added dropout.
对于此新网络 你需要注意的重要事项是我添加了丢弃层
So we remember from before,
我们之前提到
drop out randomly deletes some of
在网络训练过程中
these connections between the layers as the network is training.
丢弃会随机删除层级之间的某些连接
So what this does is it forces units in the network
作用是促使网络中的单元
to learn various features from the input data,
学习输入数据中的各种特征
and what this does is it helps the network generalize.
帮助网络泛化
To use dropout, basically you just create this operation,
要使用丢弃 正常地创建此运算
this module like you normally would,
即此模块
and give it a probability of dropping in units.
并传入丢弃单元的概率
We can add drop out and the forward pass like we would with other modules and operations,
像其他模块和运算一样 向前向传播里添加丢弃
so just self-taught dropout and pass in a tensor.
输入 self.dropout 传入一个张量
The second thing to notice here is that I'm actually
要注意的第二个事项是
returning the log softmax from the forward pass.
我从前向传播里返回了 log_softmax
I'm doing this because remember that softmax returns a probability distribution.
原因是 softmax 返回的是概率分布
So the problem with this is that a lot of times you're going to get
存在的问题是很多时候
values that are really close to zero or really close to one.
获得的值非常接近 0 或非常接近 1
Due to the imprecision of representing numbers as floating points,
由于将数字表示为浮点数不太精确
then this can lead to instabilities in calculations
这样会导致计算不稳定
and overall can build up a lot of inaccuracies.
并从整体上造成很多错误
So the way to solve this is actually take the log of the softmax,
解决办法是对 softmax 求对数
and this moves as numbers like away from zero and away from one
使数字远离 0 和 1
into normal like negative numbers, like negative four.
变成正态分布 例如负数 -4
So this helps keep computation stable, helps with precision,
有助于计算变得稳定起来 提高精确率
and in general, it's just a lot easier to work in the log-space of probability functions.
通常 处理对数空间里的概率函数轻松得多
Here, I'm creating the model like normal,
在这里 正常地创建模型
so 784 units like input units, 10 outputs,
输入单元 784 个 输出单元 10 个
I'm using two hidden layers,
使用两个隐藏层
one of the 516 units and one with 256 units,
一个有 516 个单元 一个有 256 个单元
I'm setting my dropout probability to 0.5.
将丢弃概率设为 0.5.
So since I'm using the log softmax as my output,
因为我将 log_softmax 当做输出
I need to use the negative log-likelihood loss,
我需要使用负对数似然损失函数
so I'm just using this here, there's my criterion.
使用这个作为 criterion
It works basically the same as the cross entropy loss you saw before,
和之前见到的交叉熵损失基本相同
except that it expects the log softmax as the input.
但是它需要输入为 log_softmax
As I'm also using the Adam optimizer,
我还使用了 Adam 优化器
and so like I mentioned before,
正如之前提到的
this is a variation on stochastic gradient descent that uses momentum and
它是随机梯度下降的变体 使用了动量
it ends up training your networks faster
比普通的随机梯度下降
than with just normal stochastic gradient descent.
训练速度要快
Now, I'm going to show you how to write this validation code.
现在我将演示如何编写验证代码
So the idea with validation code,
验证代码的原理是
with the validation pass is that we want to take
对于验证传播 我们希望从测试数据集中
our data from the test dataset and run it through our network,
获取数据并传入网络中
measure the loss on the test data,
衡量测试数据的损失
but also the accuracy.
还要衡量准确率
So, how well is our network actually doing on data it hasn't seen before?
即网络在之前未见过的数据上效果如何
So it's normal, it's going to start off by grabbing some images in our labels.
和之前一样 首先获取一些图像和标签
This time we're getting from the test loader,
这次从 testloader 获取
so the train loaders, these are our test images.
而不是 trainloader 这些是测试图像
So we shape our images,
调整图像大小
and then pass our images through the network.
然后将图像传入网络中
So again, these images are coming from
这些图像来自测试集
our test set and we're going to get the output for our test set,
我们将获取测试集的输出
and we can update so we can record our test loss criterion.
我们可以更新 记录测试损失 criterion
So we're not interested in doing backpropagation with this loss,
我们不打算用此损失进行反向传播
we really just want to measure the loss on the test dataset.
只是想衡量测试集的损失
So that is measuring the loss,
这些代码用来衡量损失
but now I also want to measure the accuracy,
我们还想衡量准确率
like how well our network is predicting the correct label for the test dataset.
即网络在测试数据集中预测正确标签的准确率
So here like normal, I'm going to calculate our probabilities.
在这里 正常地计算概率
So, torch.exponential.
输入 torch.exp()
So again, our output is log softmax,
同样 输出是 log_softmax,
so the inverse of the log is exponential and so this is
对数的对立面是指数
going to give us back our softmax distribution.
这样可以获得 softmax 分布
So what should this work so far, cool.
到目前为止应该一切正常 不错
Those are probabilities and you just kind of check him out, cool.
这些是概率 检查一下
They have, so 64 by 10.
大小是 64 x 10
I want to see how well our network is predicting the correct label.
我想看看网络预测正确标签的效果
So, I need to compare the correct label with what the network is predicting.
我需要比较正确标签和网络预测的标签
To get what the network is predicting I need to take
要获取网络预测结果
the highest probability from our softmax output.
我需要从 softmax 输出中获取最高概率
So this is ps.max,
输入 ps.max
I want to take the first dimension, so across here,10.
获取第一个维度 这里是 10
So what this actually does is it gives me two different tensors.
作用是获取两个不同的张量
So the first tensor are the actual probabilities,
第一个张量是实际概率
and the actual highest probabilities within
第二个张量中的最高概率是
the second tensor is the index of the highest probability.
最高概率的索引
So this index is the interesting thing,
这些索引比较有趣
because this one is actually telling us
因为会告诉我们
which class has the highest probability in the softmax output.
哪个类别在 softmax 输出中的概率最高
So since the second tensor,
第二个张量
this guy here is telling us the predicted classes,
即这个张量告诉我们预测类别
I'm going to do one so that'll give us a predicted classes,
输入 1 获得预测类别
and then we need to compare this with our true labels,
然后需要将它与真实标签比较
and I'm going to call this equality.
调用 equality
We'll see what this looks like.
看看结果如何
Equality. So, here we get
equality 获得另一个张量
this other tensor where ones are when we make the correct prediction,
1 表示预测正确
zeros where you make the incorrect prediction.
0 表示预测错误
Now to measure the accuracy, so again,
衡量准确性
the accuracy is basically just how many times did it get
准确率是指预测正确的次数
the prediction correct out of all the predictions it made.
占预测总次数的百分比
So since these are all ones and zeros,
因为这些都是 1 和 0
we basically just need to add up all the correct ones,
我们需要将所有正确项相加
so all these ones,
所有这些 1 相加
and then divide by the total number of predictions.
然后除以预测总次数
So since these are all ones,
因为这些都是 1
the really simple way to do this is just to take the mean.
简单的方法是求均值
So equality.mean.
输入 equality.mean
So a lot of times you're going to run
很多时候
it into problems with the type of tensor that you have,
张量类型会导致问题
so this is an example.
这就是一个示例
So the tensor equality has the type torch.bitetensor,
张量 equality 的类型是 torch.ByteTensor
and this is saying mean is not implemented for this type of tensor,
错误消息指出这种张量类型没有均值方法
and so, this is our problem right here, equality.mean.
问题出在 equality.mean 这了
So we actually needed to convert this to a float tensor
我们需要将这个转换为浮点张量
which does have this mean function.
浮点张量具有这个 mean 函数
So to do that, we do equality.type and give it a different data type, so float tensor.
为此 输入 equality.type 传入不同的数据类型 即 FloatTensor
So what this does is it converts the equality tensor which is a byte tensor
这行代码的作用是将 ByteTensor 类型的 equality 张量
into a float tensor and then we can get the mean from that. Now, we have our accuracy.
转换为浮点张量 然后就可以获得均值 我们算出准确率了
So we're going to want to run this validation pass,
我们将运行这个验证传播
there's a bunch of times,
次数很多
and we also need to go all the way through our test loader.
还需要一直回到 testloader
So, what I'd like to do is wrap this thing up and it's own function.
我将这部分代码封装成一个函数
So it looks something like this.
看起来是这样的
We do define validation function,
定义 validation 函数
passing a model or data,
传入模型
test loader and a criterion,
数据来自 testloader 以及 criterion
and a thing where we can sum up our accuracy,
对准确率求和
and now we're going to loop through the images and labels in our data.
循环访问数据中的图像和标签
So basically, we're looping through all the batches in our test loader,
循环访问 testloader 中的所有批次
calculating the test loss and accuracy,
计算测试损失和准确率
sum them all up and we can return these.
求和 然后返回这些值
Now that we have this as a function,
变成函数后
we can put this into our normal training loop and measured validation as we're training.
放入普通的训练循环中 在训练过程中衡量验证效果
So then, every certain number of steps which we've set by print_ every,
每隔一定数量的时间步（由 print_ every 设置）
we're going to do our validation.
我们将进行验证
So, what I'm going to do here is say torch.no_grad.
在这里输入 torch.no_grad
So, this basically turns off all gradients for all of our tensors.
目的是关闭所有张量的梯度
We want to do is because when we're doing
因为在验证过程中
validation we don't really care about the gradients, and so,
我们不关心梯度
it's just going to speed up the computation that we're doing in our validation.
这样可以加快验证算法
So, we're going to get our test loss in our accuracy from our validation function.
从验证函数里获得测试损失和准确率
It's also important to know that now that we have
现在还需要注意的是 我们有丢弃操作
dropout we don't want dropout on while we're doing validation.
但是不希望在验证时进行丢弃
So if it is on it's going to make the performance of our network look worse,
如果开启的话 会使网络的性能看起来更糟
because if you're doing inference after your training you're going to have dropout off.
因为如果要在训练之后进行推理 则需要关闭丢弃
So, we want to make sure that a dropout is off while we're doing validation.
我们要确保在验证过程中关闭丢弃
Then we can do that is by putting the model and evaluation mode.
然后输出验证模式下的模型
So, we do that with model.eval.
输入 model.eval()
Then we want to turn drop out back on,
然后再开启丢弃
so we do that with model model.train.
输入 model.train()
So to put our network in our model into a mode where it can do inference and validation,
要使网络（模型）进入推理和验证模式
we want to use model.eval,
我们需要使用 model.eval()
if we want it to be training then we say model.train.
如果要训练模型 则使用 model.train()
Just for a good measure was also set model to training up here, just in case.
为了方便衡量 还在这里设置 model.train()
Now, we can check out what this looks like.
现在可以看看效果如何了
So now, we can see we get our test laws printed out,
输出了测试损失
as well as, our accuracy.
以及准确率
So accuracy starts fairly low,
一开始准确率比较低 0.7 左右
0.7 and then over time when guys are training it gets higher.
然后当网络接受训练后 逐渐变高了
With the network trained,
网络训练之后
then we can use this for inference.
可以用来推理了
So again, making actual predictions.
即做出实际预测
So pretty much everything is the same as before,
一切基本和之前一样
we need to remember to put our model in evaluation mode to turn off drop out,
我们需要将模型放入验证模式 关闭丢弃
and we want to use with torch.no_ grad to turn off
需要使用 torch.no_ grad() 关闭梯度
our gradients and then we can actually do a forward pass and get our probability.
然后进行前向传播 获得概率
So, we'll get log softmax from here,
在这里获得 log_softmax
take the exponential get softmax and then we
求指数 获得 softmax
can get our probability distribution and actually see what we have.
然后获得概率分布 看看实际结果是什么
So, in the next part we're going to look at how to save and load models.
在下个部分 我们将学习如何保存和加载模型
It doesn't make sense to basically
没必要每次需要模型时
train a completely new model everytime you need one, and so,
都训练一个全新的模型
typically what you'll do is you'll train your model,
我们将训练模型
save it to a checkpoint which is typically
将其保存到检查点中
what a train model is called when you save it at checkpoint.
当你在检查点保存训练模型时 就叫做检查点
But you save to a checkpoint and then later you can load it up to either do
将模型保存到检查点 日后可以加载它
inference or keep training. See you in the next video.
进行推理或继续训练 下个视频见